Turn it on!
Nyalakan!
That's awesome!
Itu keren!
Have you asked a girl to the lighting ceremony yet?
Kau sudah mengajak gadis untuk upacara cahaya?
-Come on, tell me. -Huh? What about you?
- Ayolah, katakan. - Apa? Kau bagaimana?
Did he have a fight with Juno?
Dia bertengkar dengan Juno?
He's so obvious.
Sikapnya terlalu jelas.
Listen, guys.
Dengar.
Let's stop here for today and go back to school.
Ayo berhenti di sini untuk hari ini dan kembali ke sekolah.
-What? -It's only five.
- Apa? - Baru pukul lima.
The mayor told us to leave.
Wali kota suruh kita pergi.
Could that be because of what happened yesterday?
Apa itu karena kejadian kemarin?
That's right.
Benar.
There have been many devouring incidents, so it's not safe for us to stay out late.
Banyak insiden pelahapan, tak aman bagi kita keluar larut malam.
I heard a duck was killed in the neighboring town.
Kudengar bebek dibunuh di kota tetangga.
That's why we're going back to school before it gets dark.
Itu sebabnya kita kembali ke sekolah sebelum jadi gelap.
Okay.
Baiklah.
I wonder if the Festival of the Meteor will really be held.
Aku penasaran apa Festival Meteor akan diadakan.
Let's go.
Ayo pergi.
CAUGHT LIKE FLOSS IN A CANINE'S TOOTH
TERTANGKAP SEPERTI BENANG DI SELA GIGI ANJING
FLOWER
BUNGA
You must be a student from Cherryton School.
Kau pasti siswa Sekolah Cherryton.
Mr. Mayor...
Tn. Wali Kota...
You have to go back to school now.
Kau harus kembali ke sekolah sekarang.
Yes.
Ya.
Creating a town where everybody can live in safety
Membuat kota tempat semua orang hidup aman
is my duty as a mayor.
adalah tugasku sebagai wali kota.
Everybody's already left. I didn't realize that.
Semua sudah pergi. Aku tak sadari itu.
I'm so alone.
Aku sendirian.
Well, I've always been alone.
Aku selalu sendirian.
Even if I get devoured, no one would probably notice that I'm gone.
Walau aku dilahap, mungkin tak akan ada yang tahu aku tak ada.
Haru...
Haru...
Legoshi.
Legoshi.
It's really hard to understand this gray wolf boy.
Sangat sulit memahami anak serigala kelabu ini.
He turned the cold shoulder to me the other day,
Dia tak mengacuhkanku tempo hari,
-and now he shows this verve. -Ah...
kini dia tunjukkan perhatiannya.
Shoot! I should talk to her at her eye level.
Sial! Aku harus bicara kepadanya setinggi matanya.
-How are you? -I thought you'd already left.
- Apa kabar? - Kukira kau sudah pergi.
Yeah...
Ya.
Ah... Can I go home with you today?
Apa aku boleh pulang denganmu hari ini?
Sure, but what happened all of a sudden?
Tentu, tetapi apa yang terjadi tiba-tiba?
Because it's dangerous outside.
Karena berbahaya di luar.
Was he actually trying to be funny?
Apa dia berusaha melucu?
I wonder if I should have joked about it like, "Look who's talking!"
Aku penasaran apa harus kucandai soal itu seperti, "Lihat siapa yang bicara!"
Hey, what the hell is wrong with you, Legoshi?
Ada apa denganmu, Legoshi?
Sorry, sorry.
Maaf.
Stand clear of the closing doors, please.
Jauhi pintu tertutup.
Sorry...
Maaf...
Legoshi...
Legoshi...
I felt this when I met you for the first time...
aku merasakan ini saat bertemu kau pertama kali...
I don't really know what you're thinking.
aku tak tahu apa yang kau pikirkan.
You don't?
Kau tak tahu?
The first day...
Hari pertama...
It was hot today, wasn't it?
Panas hari ini, bukan?
It's gonna be a little cooler tomorrow,
Akan agak lebih sejuk besok,
-so it'll be more comfort-- -Why do you avoid talking about that day?
- jadi akan lebih nyaman... - Kau tak mau membicarakan hari itu?
You can laugh at it now that a rabbit you just met
Kau bisa mentertawakannya bahwa kelinci yang baru kautemui
tried to sleep with you, because we are friends now, right?
coba tidur denganmu, karena kini kita berteman, bukan?
I can't just let it go that easily.
Aku tak bisa lupakan semudah itu.
It was something unforgettable to me, so...
Hal itu tak terlupakan bagiku.
I can't do anything but just keep inside
Aku hanya bisa menyimpannya dalam hati
my heart, and I don't want to forget about it.
dan tak mau melupakannya.
I want you to value yourself as much as I value that memory.
Aku ingin kau menghargai dirimu setinggi aku menghargai kenangan itu.
Please don't... give yourself to anyone like that.
Jangan menyerahkan dirimu kepada siapa pun seperti itu.
I don't want to hear that, especially from a wolf like you.
Aku tak mau mendengarnya, khususnya dari serigala sepertimu.
DO NOT ENTER
DILARANG MASUK
You've never known what it's like to live a life
Kau tak pernah tahu rasanya menjalani hidup
with the constant fear of death.
dengan selalu merasa ketakutan.
I may be devoured
Aku mungkin dilahap
before even being loved by someone.
bahkan sebelum dicintai seseorang.
You've never had such a fear,
Kau tak pernah merasa takut seperti itu,
so you will never understand that about me.
jadi kau tak akan pahami itu tentangku.
Let go of me. I'll ride in other train car.
Lepaskan aku. Aku akan naik gerbong lain.
-You can't. We should talk. -We have nothing to talk about.
- Tak bisa. Kita harus bicara. - Tak ada yang harus kita bicarakan.
-I just told you the truth. -But--
- Aku baru katakan sebenarnya. - Tetapi...
Stop lecturing me as if you understand me. Let go of my hand!
Jangan menceramahiku ibarat kau memahamiku. Lepaskan tanganku!
Then, don't go away.
Jadi, jangan pergi.
-What the hell? Just let me go! -No!
- Ada apa? Lepaskan aku! - Tidak!
-Let go of me! -I won't.
- Lepaskan aku! - Aku tak mau.
-He's assaulting her! -Is there any carnivore who can help?
- Dia menyerang gadis itu! - Ada karnivora yang membantu?
You, the wolf!
Kau, serigala!
What are you doing?
Sedang apa kau?
I was just talking with her. I wasn't doing anything...
Aku cuma mengobrol dengannya. Aku tak lakukan apa-apa...
Let's get out of here!
Ayo pergi dari sini!
-What? Why? -Now!
- Apa? Kenapa? - Sekarang!
Hey, wait!
Hei, tunggu!
Why are we running away? They'll be more suspicious...
Kenapa kita kabur? Mereka akan lebih curiga...
Are you stupid?
Apa kau bodoh?
Carnivores could get caught just by using any kind of force
Karnivora bisa ditangkap hanya untuk gunakan kekerasan apa pun
on herbivores these days.
pada herbivora akhir-akhir ini.
-Oh, I almost kicked you. -You're such a pain!
- Aku hampir menendangmu. - Kau menyebalkan!
Are you sensitive or thick-skinned? Make up your mind!
Apa kau peka atau bebal? Ambil keputusan!
I'm still trying to figure that out myself.
Aku masih berusaha mencari tahu itu.
Because we are so different, I'm wondering how I should interact with you.
Karena kita sangat berbeda, aku ingin tahu caraku berinteraksi denganmu.
Will you stop being attentive to me in a situation like this?
Apa kau bisa jangan penuh perhatian kepadaku dalam situasi begini?
Instead, just run as fast as you can and take me away!
Alih-alih, lari secepat mungkin dan bawa aku pergi!
Or they'll get you! Hurry!
Atau kau akan ditangkap! Cepat!
Hey! Stop right there!
Hei! Berhenti di sana!
In front of the girl I fell in love with for the first time,
Di depan gadis yang kucintai untuk pertama kalinya,
I could feel confident about myself as a wolf for the first time.
aku bisa merasa yakin akan diriku sebagai serigala untuk pertama kali.
I have no idea where I'm heading to.
Aku tak tahu menuju ke mana.
I don't know what others think about us, either.
Entah apa yang dipikirkan orang lain tentang kami.
There should be a way.
Pasti ada cara.
I'm just gonna keep moving forward.
Aku akan terus maju.
Where are they?
Di mana mereka?
Even in this kind of situation, he's trying not to touch me.
Bahkan dalam situasi ini, dia berusaha tak menyentuhku.
-Hey, over there! -What? Really?
- Hei, di sana! - Apa? Sungguh?
I thought they were here...
Kukira mereka di sini...
Hey...
Hei...
Can we go now?
Apa kita bisa pergi sekarang?
Haru... Do you fear like your life is in danger
Haru, apa kau merasa hidupmu terancam
by being with me here, right now?
dengan bersamaku saat ini?
I didn't notice until now,
Aku tak memerhatikan hingga saat ini,
that carnivores growl in the throat
geraman karnivora dalam tenggorokan
as they talk.
saat mereka bicara.
Why are you letting out
Kenapa kau keluarkan
such a low growl with such a gentle look?
geraman rendah dengan pandangan lembut itu?
I told you!
Sudah kukatakan!
Be sensitive or be thick-skinned. Not both.
Bersikap peka atau bebal. Jangan keduanya.
Because you ask such a question in anervous tone,
Karena kau tanya dengan gugup,
everybody gets scared of you.
kau jadi ditakuti.
I read about it in a magazine,
Aku baca soal itu di majalah,
carnivores can never be too cheerful if you wanna be popular.
karnivora tak pernah bisa terlalu riang jika ingin populer.
You know what that means?
Kau tahu apa artinya?
Yeah, I get it.
Ya, aku paham.
It's wrong to keep it a secret anymore.
Salah untuk merahasiakannya lagi.
I have to tell her about that night.
Aku harus memberi tahu soal malam itu.
Maybe now is the time to confess.
Mungkin kini saatnya mengaku.
-Look... -Listen--
- Begini... - Dengar...
...I was once almost devoured by a carnivore.
...aku pernah hampir dilahap karnivora.
At school. I couldn't see his face though, because it was too dark.
Di sekolah. Aku tak bisa melihat wajahnya, karena terlalu gelap.
Look at this scar.
Lihat bekas luka ini.
Remember? I had a bandage when I met you for the first time.
Ingat? Aku pakai perban saat bertemu kau pertama kali.
That's...
Itu...
I told you that I didn't remember what happened,
Sudah kukatakan aku tak ingat kejadiannya,
but I was lying.
tetapi aku berbohong.
...a scar I gave you.
...bekas luka dariku.
I can't tell her.
Aku tak bisa memberi tahu dia.
I'm glad that I wasn't killed.
Aku senang aku tak dibunuh.
I don't feel the fear of death when I hang out with you.
Aku tak merasa takut mati saat bersamamu.
I can swear this.
Aku bisa bersumpah soal ini.
Hey, smile!
Hei, tersenyumlah!
-Hey, come on! Give me your smile! -I can't tell her now...
- Ayo! Beri senyumanmu. - Aku tak bisa beri tahu dia sekarang.
If I tell her my secret,
Jika kuberi tahu rahasiaku,
we'll probably be over.
mungkin hubungan kami usai.
Until the time comes, I will keep admonishing myself.
Hingga saatnya tiba, aku akan terus menegur diriku.
-Haru... -What?
- Haru... - Apa?
Thank you...
Terima kasih.
for today.
Untuk hari ini.
You don't have to thank me, but just be happy. Smile!
Kau tak harus berterima kasih, tetapi senanglah. Tersenyum!
Smile...
Tersenyum...
Oh, come on! You're making a fake smile on purpose, aren't you?
Ayolah! Kau pura-pura tersenyum dengan sengaja, ya?
Can I walk with you in the sunlight a bit longer?
Apa aku boleh berjalan denganmu di bawah sinar mentari lebih lama?
STUDENT ID - NAME: JUNO CLASSIFICATION: GRAY WOLF
KARTU PELAJAR - NAMA: JUNO PENGGOLONGAN: SERIGALA KELABU
For real?
Sungguh?
I heard that Bill did that to you.
Kudengar Bill yang melakukan itu padamu.
I hope it doesn't leave a scar.
Semoga tak tinggalkan bekas luka.
This isn't the same as the scar on your back.
Ini tak sama dengan bekas luka di punggungmu.
What do you want?
Kau mau apa?
If you have something to say, say it.
Jika ada yang ingin kaukatakan, katakanlah.
I have nothing to say... for now.
Tak ada yang ingin kukatakan, saat ini.
Hey, what's wrong with them?
Ada apa dengan mereka?
What's going on?
Ada apa?
Are they getting along or not?
Mereka akur atau tidak?
They're not.
Tidak.
Don't bring your personal problems into the club.
Jangan bawa masalah pribadi ke klub.
I'm telling this to all of you! The Festival of the Meteor is approaching,
Kukatakan ini kepada kalian! Festival Meteor sebentar lagi,
but we are not working as a team at all.
tetapi kita tak bekerja sebagai tim.
Will you guys be able to perform perfectly without any mistakes?
Apa kalian bisa tampil dengan sempurna tanpa salah?
I'm sorry!
Maafkan aku!
I'm late.
Aku terlambat.
Juno!
Juno!
Juno! If you're gonna be late,
Juno! Jika kau akan terlambat,
you have to let me or one of the seniors know.
kau harus beri tahu aku atau salah satu anak kelas tiga.
I'm sorry.
Maaf.
My classmate, a sloth, had to rush to the bathroom,
Teman sekelasku, kungkang, harus bergegas ke kamar mandi,
so I carried her there.
jadi kugendong dia ke sana.
-It can't be helped, then. -You are so kind.
- Itu tak bisa dihindari. - Kau baik sekali.
But it's just an excuse,
Tetapi hanya alasan,
so please let me do the cleaning of the rehearsal room today.
jadi biarkan aku membersihkan ruang latihan hari ini.
Sheila, what's going on?
Sheila, ada apa?
You told me that Juno was isolated from the other members.
Katamu Juno dikucilkan dari anggota lain.
She's been making a lot of efforts these days.
Dia berupaya keras akhir-akhir ini.
Legoshi!
Legoshi!
I saw the dino!
Aku melihat dinosaurusnya!
Because the art team does a great job,
Karena hasil kerja tim seni bagus,
we, the actors, can do our best dancing.
kita, para aktor, bisa tampil terbaik dalam menari.
That's great.
Itu hebat.
She's looking at nobody but Legoshi.
Dia cuma menatap Legoshi.
The Festival of the Meteor is the biggest summer event.
Festival Meteor adalah acara musim panas terbesar.
Let's do our best on our practice today!
Ayo berlatih sebaik mungkin hari ini!
Yeah!
Ya!
Okay, let's warm up!
Ayo lakukan pemanasan!
Juno pulled a team together.
Juno mengumpulkan tim.
Juno.
Juno.
Thank you for today.
Terima kasih untuk hari ini.
Aren't you done cleaning yet?
Kau belum selesai membersihkan?
Isn't it too dark with just one light on?
Bukankah terlalu gelap hanya dengan satu lampu?
Because wolves are nocturnal,
Karena serigala hewan malam,
I feel better when it's dark.
aku merasa lebih baik saat gelap.
Right...
Benar.
You're a wolf.
Kau serigala.
That's not the only reason.
Bukan cuma itu alasannya.
There's one spotlight,
Ada satu lampu sorot,
and there are two actors.
dan ada dua aktor.
Rouis, would you help me with my practice?
Rouis, kau bisa bantu aku dengan latihanku?
Just two of us, for the first time.
Hanya kami berdua, untuk pertama kalinya.
Okay.
Baiklah.
One, two, three. One, two, three.
Satu, dua, tiga. Satu, dua, tiga.
One, two, three.
Satu, dua, tiga.
You're doing it the wrong way.
Gerakanmu salah.
Did I go too fast?
Apa aku terlalu cepat?
It was rather rough.
Itu agak kasar.
Your performance would fascinate the audience,
Penampilanmu akan memukau penonton,
but the harmony with others is important.
tetapi harmoni dengan yang lain itu penting.
Give me your hand.
Berikan tanganmu.
Well, as long as you cheerfully dance,
Selama kau menari dengan riang,
guys will be fascinated.
para pemuda akan terpukau.
So you really don't need to pursue perfection.
Kau tak harus mengejar kesempurnaan.
What do you mean by that?
Apa maksudmu dengan itu?
Oh, sorry.
Maaf.
Did that sound like an insult?
Apa itu seperti hinaan?
I realize...
Aku menyadari...
Hey...
Hei...
...that you hate me.
...bahwa kau membenciku.
Or perhaps,
Atau mungkin,
you just hate carnivores.
kau cuma membenci karnivora.
What do you think you're doing?
Kau sedang apa?
Are you going to kiss me or what?
Apa kau mau menciumku?
Of course not.
Tentu tidak.
If I kissed you on the lips now,
Jika kucium bibirmu sekarang,
and if I couldn't resist my impulse to eat you,
jika aku tak bisa menahan naluriku untuk melahapku,
I'd be in trouble.
aku dalam masalah.
I'm not into you. I'm in love with Legoshi.
Aku tak menyukaimu. Aku jatuh cinta dengan Legoshi.
I am declaring a war, Rouis.
Aku menyatakan perang, Rouis.
I will be the next Beastar.
Aku akan jadi Beastar berikutnya.
I will make a new peaceful era for carnivores
Akan kubuat era kedamaian baru bagi karnivora
and Legoshi senpai will be mine.
dan Legoshi akan jadi milikku.
Do you still want to boast about your strength?
Apa kau masih mau memamerkan kekuatanmu?
I'd probably feel better being devoured by you
Mungkin aku merasa lebih baik dilahap olehmu
rather than Bill or Legoshi.
daripada Bill atau Legoshi.
I will...
Aku tak akan
never bare my fangs against you.
pernah menunjukkan taringku kepadamu.
Female wolves do not like conflict.
Serigala betina tak suka konflik.
Really?
Sungguh?
A greedy female wolf like you must be different from others.
Serigala betina rakus sepertimu pasti berbeda dari yang lain.
Is it wrong to be greedy?
Apa salah untuk rakus?
No, I didn't mean that.
Tidak, maksudku bukan begitu.
Just...
Hanya...
Your greediness is based on your massive confidence.
Kerakusanmu berdasarkan percaya dirimu yang amat besar.
Beauty, status, and a male.
Kecantikan, status, dan jantan.
You think you can get whatever you wish.
Kau kira kau bisa dapatkan semua keinginanmu.
You already have the first one, beauty,
Kau sudah dapat yang pertama, kecantikan,
but I will not let you have the second one.
tetapi aku tak akan membiarkanmu mendapat yang kedua.
And the third one. Your favorite male, Legoshi...
Dan yang ketiga. Pemuda kesukaanmu, Legoshi...
He is much harder to obtain than you think.
Dia lebih sulit didapat dibanding perkiraanmu.
What makes you say that?
Kenapa kau katakan itu?
I will definitely make Legoshi mine!
Aku akan menjadikan Legoshi milikku!
Just watch him, and you will see what I mean.
Amati saja dia, kau akan tahu apa maksudku.
Well, it will be a good ordeal for an overconfident girl like you.
Akan jadi siksaan bagus untuk gadis yang terlalu percaya diri sepertimu.
You have split ends on your tail.
Ada ujung terbelah di ekormu.
Don't pull it out, it will hurt.
Jangan ditarik, akan sakit.
I won't.
Tidak.
Does he have... a girlfriend?
Apa dia punya pacar?
Everybody, let's go back to school now!
Teman-teman, ayo kembali ke sekolah!
It's already dark out here.
Sudah gelap di luar sini.
Rouis has already left.
Rouis sudah pergi.
Dom is so energetic.
Dom sangat bersemangat.
-Hello. -Hi, Juno.
- Halo. - Hai, Juno.
Thank you for waiting. The actors are ready to leave, too.
Terima kasih mau menunggu. Para aktor juga siap pergi.
Legoshi,
Legoshi,
I did pretty well in the rehearsal,
aku bisa berlatih dengan baik,
thanks to your support.
berkat dukunganmu.
No problem at all. I didn't do anything.
Tak masalah. Aku tak lakukan apa-apa.
His facial expressions are the same when he talks to me or to others.
Mimik wajahnya sama saat dia bicara kepadaku atau hewan lain.
Let's go, then.
Ayo kita pergi.
Oh! The meteor has been completed already!
Meteor sudah lengkap!
Yeah, you're right.
Ya, kau benar.
If you place a lit candle at the meteor with someone you love,
Jika kau taruh lilin menyala pada meteor dengan orang yang kaucintai,
the couple will be blessed.
pasangan itu akan diberkati.
Do you believe that?
Apa kau percaya itu?
I don't know...
Entahlah...
It'd be great if it were true.
Akan bagus jika itu benar.
The couple will be blessed...
Pasangan akan diberkati...
Ah, um... Legoshi.
Legoshi.
On the festival day,
Pada hari festival,
would you be--
apa kau mau jadi...
What?
Apa?
We lost the power... This is bad!
Listrik mati. Ini buruk!
Is everybody all right?
Semua baik-baik saja?
Legoshi? Where are you?
Legoshi? Di mana kau?
I'm here. I will hold your hand, okay?
Aku di sini. Aku akan pegang tanganmu, ya?
Yes...
Ya.
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
I think it's a power outage. Don't worry.
Kurasa pemadaman listrik. Jangan cemas.
We, the nocturnal, will protect you.
Kami, hewan malam, akan melindungimu.
Els! Are you all right?
Els! Kau baik-baik saja?
Yeah, I'm okay...
Ya, aku baik-baik saja.
Let's come and get together in one place.
Ayo berkumpul di satu tempat.
Everybody, get in the circle!
Semuanya, masuk ke lingkaran!
Isn't the power back yet?
Apa listrik sudah menyala?
I'm scared. I can't see anything.
Aku takut. Tak bisa melihat apa pun.
It's all right. The power will be back soon.
Tak apa-apa. Listrik akan kembali menyala.
No wonder they get frightened.
Pantas saja mereka takut.
Devour incidents always occur
Insiden pelahapan selalu terjadi
when it's completely dark outside.
saat di luar sungguh gelap.
How many of us are here today?
Ada berapa anggota kita hari ini?
Let's see...
Mari lihat...
Thanks, but it's okay. I'm almost done, so you can go back now.
Terima kasih, tak apa-apa. Aku hampir selesai, kau bisa kembali.
Aoba, sorry! I have to go. Please take care of them.
Aoba, maaf! Aku harus pergi. Tolong urus mereka.
-Hey! -I'll be back soon!
- Hei! - Aku segera kembali!
How come he could leave us like this?
Kenapa dia bisa tinggalkan kita seperti ini?
Haru!
Haru!
Haru?
Haru?
She's not here...
Dia tak di sini...
Where is she?
Di mana dia?
Calm down. I still smell her, so she should be around.
Tenang. Aku masih menciumnya, jadi dia pasti di sekitar sini.
Concentrate.
Berkonsentrasilah.
Track it. Track her scent.
Lacak itu. Lacak aromanya.
Please stay safe.
Tetaplah aman.
-What a relief... -Rouis!
- Syukurlah... - Rouis!
I'm so glad you came!
Aku senang kau datang!
Legoshi?
Legoshi?
I... am sorry. Oh, gosh. I'm so sorry.
Maaf. Astaga. Aku minta maaf.
I thought you were...
Kukira kau...
It's okay. I'm glad you are safe.
Tak apa-apa. Aku senang kau aman.
I couldn't see anything at all. I'm sorry.
Aku tak bisa melihat apa-apa. Maaf.
I know. Are you hurt?
Aku tahu. Apa kau cedera?
Your uniform got dirty. Here, use this.
Seragammu kotor. Ini, gunakan ini.
-I'm so sorry. -It's okay. Take it.
- Maafkan aku. - Tak apa-apa. Ambillah.
-Thank you. -Have you been here since?
- Terima kasih. - Kau di sini sejak tadi?
It can't be...
Tak mungkin...
A wolf and a rabbit?
Serigala dan kelinci?
Of course not! That's not possible!
Tentu tidak! Itu mustahil!
But... Wait...
Tetapi... Tunggu...
No way!
Mustahil!
Subtitle translation by Kanako Murakoshi
Terjemahan subtitle oleh Mimi Larasati Bonnetto